<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
			<title>Psychonaut</title>
			<description></description>
			<link>http://adityavm.github.com</link>
			<lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 18:30:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
			<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 18:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
	
			<item>
					<title>On What People Want</title>
					<description><![CDATA[
						&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t know what they want until you’ve given it to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then they don’t know what they want next: they think it’s more of what they liked last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;—&lt;a href="http://neil-gaiman.tumblr.com/post/20439013505/do-you-ever-feel-pressured-by-the-changing-desires-of"&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt; (via &lt;a href="http://notes.byjasm.in/74"&gt;Jasmin Wong&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
					]]></description>
					<link>http://neil-gaiman.tumblr.com/post/20439013505/do-you-ever-feel-pressured-by-the-changing-desires-of</link>
					<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			</item><item>
					<title>Comics to Movies, and Back to Comics Again</title>
					<description><![CDATA[
						&lt;p&gt;The latest Hollywood trend has been to take well-known and established comics and turn them into blockbuster summer flicks. In fact, that has been so successful that they've started doing the same for &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Walking_Dead_(TV_series)"&gt;television serials&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside to this is that comics are slowly but finally becoming mainstream, and getting the attention they should as an art-form. I know people who see a movie, realise it's based off a comic, then try to get their hands on the comic books and end up liking the latter more than the movie (quite like how book-based-movies work). Comics are just books, but visual. They're the bridge between books and movies, if you want to see the progression of story-telling. Books to comics to animated features to live-action movies. And I still look at comics as a "pure" art-form, undiluted and uncorrupted by capitalism and commercial agendas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must confess though that I'm not a big comic-book reader/collector. It's partly because I didn't have access to them as a child and partly because the allure of books, formal language and story-telling was far stronger than the more informal, leave-lesser-to-the-imagination nature of comic books. And yes, the moment you make something even remotely visual, you're taking away from the imagination of the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside to this is that the movies being made are too mainstream and must-appeal-to-all-ages. Even Nolan's Batman franchise — gritty and dark as it is — has the family-movie feel to it. The real comic-to-movie successes (I think) are the ones that have flown under the radar: movies like &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watchmen_(film)"&gt;Watchmen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kick-Ass_(film)"&gt;Kick-Ass&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. They aren't your family-trip kind of movies, but they're good movies nonetheless, and the comics are so much better. None of this High School Musical crap, but stories with real socipolitical commentary. These are the kind of comics that the mainstream will never see unless someone shows them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the good thing about being alive in the year 2012 is how easily available things are. Getting your hands on a comic is as simple as downloading an iPad app and then searching for your comic. As &lt;a href="http://jasonsantamaria.com/articles/comic-books-on-the-ipad"&gt;Jason Santa Maria rightly said&lt;/a&gt;, comics have gained from having made the transition to the iPad. But I still don't think the size and nature of the screen is good enough to completely enjoy edge-to-edge illustrations. But hey, something is better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the movie version of Kick-Ass was &lt;em&gt;seriously&lt;/em&gt; toned down, and even then people had problems with it. The hypocrisy of our time is pretty much summed up in a single line from the movie's &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kick-Ass_(film)#Controversy"&gt;Wikipedia page&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christopher Mintz-Plasse expressed surprise that people were angry about the language, but did not seem to be offended that Hit-Girl kills many people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
					]]></description>
					<link>http://adityavm.github.com/pages/permalinks/5.html</link>
					<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			</item><item>
					<title>Symbols, Everlasting</title>
					<description><![CDATA[
						&lt;p&gt;Interesting look at villainy. Could also be a justification-in-disguise of why Curtis went from calling himself a "superhero" to a "villain". Personally, his definition of a villain is what I would call an anti-hero. Villains are defined as people who cause damage and harm to people and things around them. It's not about hurting a few to save many; that's as selfish a reason as doing something just because you want to. Nothing a villain does is for the good of those around him, not in the long or short run. So maybe Curtis should start calling himself a symbol, rather than a superhero or a villain. Allying himself to either side seems counter-logical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, since he brings up the Batman reference, I should also point out the Joker who was a villain not out of some personal "ego, greed, lust, or the desire for power", but because as Alfred put it, "Some men just want to watch the world burn."&lt;/p&gt;
					]]></description>
					<link>http://dcurt.is/villainy</link>
					<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			</item><item>
					<title>Much Ado About Svbtle</title>
					<description><![CDATA[
						&lt;p&gt;As someone who writes for self-gratification, blogging networks and the state of today's blogs in general, have always annoyed me. So much so that I have gone out of my way to stop reading &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; of them. Books are pretty much all I read these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first ever blogging network that I came across was &lt;a href="http://9rules.com/"&gt;9rules&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I didn't understand what the point of grouping up blogs into a "network" was. Sure, it had the potential to get you more readers, and once you were a part of a network, all the "qualities" that it stood for were somehow automatically imbibed into your blog as well. But then what? It wasn't making you a better writer or improving your writing. It wasn't telling us something we didn't already know; just a different way of looking at things we already knew. And that's what every blog eventually becomes, even if it wasn't how it started out: an mess of opinions about or links to existing stuff. Rare is the blog that tells us something new. Like if Phileas Fogg ever wrote one, that would be truly something worth reading and looking forward to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is why &lt;a href="http://dcurt.is/codename-svbtle"&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt; interests me. Apart from being the hardest name to type that I've come across in a while, it's the &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/03/24/forget-todays-drama-dustin-curtis-svbtle-is-trying-to-push-blogging-forward/"&gt;benefits that come along with it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to offer copy-editing and other benefits to help improve the writing of members on the Network, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a network that looks like it's actually going to actively &lt;em&gt;do something&lt;/em&gt; for its writers rather than just give them more viewers and the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dcurtis/status/186897703198928898"&gt;occasional plug from Curtis himself&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, how it plays out in the next few months will be interesting because those "benefits" will be hard to scale as more writers join up. Although knowing Curtis, I doubt there will be too many to begin with. I haven't signed up for an invite because I know I won't get in &lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. That and the fact that I don't want to be on the clock or feel responsible for writing — I like the freedom to be lethargic, to passively observe the daily workings of the world without feeling the need to say something about it at every step of the way &lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I found an engine I can tweak and play around with myself. I just hate how I find these things mere weeks away from my exams every single time.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look Maw! I'm all grown up!&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
					]]></description>
					<link>http://adityavm.github.com/pages/permalinks/3.html</link>
					<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			</item><item>
					<title>Speechhub</title>
					<description><![CDATA[
						&lt;p&gt;Writing posts in Wordpress irks me like few other things do. I've figured that half the reason why I don't write/post/publish/whatever as frequently as I would like to is because the mere thought of having to look at Wordpress' admin panel annoys me. So today I found &lt;a href="https://github.com/alvesjnr/speechhub"&gt;Speechhub&lt;/a&gt;, and after &lt;a href="https://github.com/adityavm/speechhub"&gt;modifying it a little&lt;/a&gt;, I have my new Shorts-like blog up on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty basic, but that's the idea. I've taken the concept behind &lt;a href="http://dcurt.is/codename-svbtle"&gt;Svbtle&lt;/a&gt; as a spiritual guide to how I will approach blogging, and we'll see where it goes. And of course, I'll be fixing up how this place looks as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
					]]></description>
					<link>https://github.com/alvesjnr/speechhub</link>
					<pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
